Andrew Hamlin

Software Engineering Leader Simsbury, CT 06070 | Phone (860) 810 - 6538 aahamlin@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin

Professional Summary

Engineering manager with 20+ years experience in development and delivery of distributed systems and applications. A servant leader who emphasizes communication, collaboration, ownership, and continuous improvement, while coaching XP values such as pairing, TDD/BDD, and CI/CD. Successfully manages processes in 5 to 50+ person product teams, using Agile/Scrum, Kanban, and SAFe, in partnership with Product, Design, and others, that have resulted in more effective forecasting, better risk mitigation, and consistent performance against OKRs.

Work Experience

Technical Co-Founder - Unplugg Enterprises, Easthampton, MA Apr 2019 - Dec 2019 Developed business plan, ran customer development studies, prototyped iOS & Android app with Dart, Flutter, Swift, Java, AWS AppSync (GraphQL/DynamoDB) and Adobe XD.

Senior Software Engineering Manager - Gerber Technology, Tolland, CT Apr 2018 - Dec 2019 Championed improvements across the SDLC such as team-based design & estimation, code reviews and Agile Sprint planning: resulting in 86% fewer defects and 70% more completed work. Managed 8 directs & 20 offshore contractors. On-boarded 12 developers via acquisition.

Software Development Manager - Sailpoint Technologies, Austin, TX Dec 2016 - Mar 2018 Collaborated with peers and Product managers to design and deliver feature sets in Angular & Java across 5 teams. Automated analysis of Jira project stats and development metrics in Python. Established workflow for new localization partner; added 4 languages. Introduced security threat modeling during design. Scrum master of 2 teams, totaling ~16 dev & test engineers. Managed 8 directs. Led recruitment & on-boarding of 4 new hires.

Software Engineering Manager - Caradigm, Bellevue, WA / Remote Jul 2013 - Nov 2016 Led teams from planning to on-time delivery of two new products, as lead developer and scrum master. Envisioned and deployed CI/CD pipeline enabling isolated polyglot build & test environments for full-stack applications including Javascript, C#/.NET, Java, Python, PowerShell, and SQL with automated testing and reporting capabilities.

Sustaining Engineering Manager - Caradigm, Bellevue, WA / Remote Jul 2012 - Jun 2013 Established Kanban process that delivered 50+ releases to production in clinical healthcare environments and meeting 100% of our SLAs. Earned **2013 Caradigm Employee Recognition Award** for improving our customer satisfaction scores, as measured by KLAS Research.

Software Development Engineer II - Microsoft Corporation, Andover, MA Jul 2010 - Jun 2012 Designed SOA architecture and led transition from Java to C#/.NET and PowerShell.

Principal Software Engineer - Sentillion, Andover, MA / Remote Dec 1999 - Jun 2010 Developed SSO/IAM platform on Linux clusters in Java & Perl. Automated bare metal installation to fulfill initial 300 unit sales. Fixed LB algorithm that eliminated service disruptions and maintenance cost. Refactored HA solution to use OSS, saving \$1K/server in licensing.

Education

Daniel Webster College, Nashua, NH B.S., Management and Information Technology